那么，你们在卡丁冲击的投资，
So, the majority
of your investment in...
大部分将用于初期的建设
Kart Attack wiII go towards
initiaI construction costs.
这部分成本将通过收益赚回
A percentage of which wiII be
paid back through earnings
细节参见之前我给你们的小册子
which are outIined in the
bookIet I handed out earIier.
主要在A2、D5和E15，
PrimariIy in sections
A2, D5 and E15,
另见附录9、11、12
but aIso in the appendix
sections 9, 11 and 1 2.
听着，我知道我一下子
给你们的数字太多
Listen, I know I'm throwing
a Iot of numbers at you
也许会把你们弄迷糊了
and that can get confusing.
所以，让我给你们点可见的东西
So, Iet me give you
something a IittIe more visuaI
帮你们理解我们
要做的是什么
to heIp show you
what we're aII about.
沃尔特，我们准备好了
WaIter, we're ready.
哦，我的天
Oh, my.
我搭档，沃尔特，穿的是
我们的赛车服原型
My partner, WaIter, is wearing
our prototype racing gear.
这是每个员工的标准配置
It's standard issue
for aII empIoyees.
- 酷
- 这只是原型
- CooI.
- It's just a prototype.
真正的制服
将是防火材料制成，
The actuaI uniform
wiII be fIame retardant,
这是好事，是不是？
which is a good thing,
don't you think?
因为你酷的冒烟了，
朋友。辍―！
'Cause you are smoking,
my friend. Tss-ss!
所以，总结起来，
So, to sum up,
卡丁冲击，
不止是卡丁车道
Kart Attack, much more
than a go-cart track.
这是家人在琳琅满目的小食店
It's a famiIy sharing
an ice cream cone
分享蛋筒冰淇淋
at our fuIIy-stocked snack bar.
这是孩子们玩最新电游的
It's a safe and secure pIace
安全有保障的场所
for your kids to pIay
the Iatest video games.
这是在我们的信仰自由间里
It's a bar mitzvah in one of our
faith-friendIy function rooms.
举行犹太受诫礼（13岁男子）
- But most of aII, it's...
- Fun!
我们希望你是下一个
We hope you'II be the next
体验卡丁冲击的人！
谢谢
to experience a ''Kart Attack''!
Thank you.
太棒了，伙计们
That was awesome, guys.
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
我本想给沃尔特
的入场加点烟雾效果的，
I was gonna use a fog machine
for WaIter's entrance,
不过后来一想这是私人场所，
再说――
but I figured it was
an intimate setting, and--
不，这很好。谢谢
No, it was great.
Thanks.
那么，我们能商量几分钟吗？
So, couId we just have a few minutes
to taIk things over?
当然，好好聊
Yeah, taIk away.
我来拆道具
I'II just be
breaking down the set.
好的
AII right.
- 那么，你怎么想？
- 唔，非常好
- So, what do you think?
- WeII, it was very good.
- 非常专业
- 是的，我惊呆了
- Very professionaI.
- Yeah, I'm surprised.
我是说，他们显然下了功夫
I mean, they've cIearIy done
their research.
- 是的，他们下了。那么，咱们干吗？
- 哦，不！
- Yes, they have. So, we in?
- Oh, no!
为什么？
Why?
看，亲爱的
Look, honey,
我说了听他们的方案，
我也听了，
I said that I wouId hear
their proposaI and I did,
可什么也改变不了
那是卡丁车的事实
but nothing in it changes the fact
that it's go-carts.
我知道，可是――拜托，
这才是有意思的地方
I know, but-- come on,
that's what's fun about it.
再说，这是个可靠的投资
PIus, it's a soIid investment.
而且，他们在想
给辆卡丁车取你的名字
Besides, they're thinking of naming
a go-cart after you.
真的。“黛比拉号”
They are.
''The Debra.''
一辆黑色的
It's bIack.
这真是每个少女的梦想
That is every girI's dream.
拜托，我不能让他们空欢喜一场
Come on, I can't
turn 'em down,
他们忙活了半天。
叫我怎么跟他们说？
they did a show and everything.
What am I gonna teII 'em?
我不知道，告诉他们你想怎么样。
我得去接孩子了
I don't know, teII 'em what you want.
I gotta go pick up the kids.
孩子――什么时候他们身上
的投资能见着个子啊？
Kids-- when we gonna see a dime
from that investment?
跟他们说去吧
Just go taIk to them.
我肯定他们接受得了的，
他们是专业人士
I'm sure they can handIe it,
they're professionaIs.
呜，呜，呜……
Whoo, whoo, whoo...
- 嘿
- 嘿，伙计！好啦！
- Hey.
- Hey, man! AII right!
那么，黛比拉怎么说？
她来不来？
So, what did Debra say?
Is she on board?
- 噢，不是那么回事
- 什么？
- Awww, not reaIIy.
- What?
什么？
What?
你说什么呢，伙计？
她说我们干得很好
What are you taIking about, man?
She said we did a great job.
眼神交流得很好
I had good
eye contact going.
我还做了总结手势，
这可是必杀技！
I did the summary hands,
it was kiIIer stuff!
我知道，我知道。
她就是――她不上钩
I know, I know.
She just-- she wasn't biting.
那你呢？
What about you?
你想就这么过一辈子？
You want to Iive Iike this
the rest of your Iife?
我知道，我知道
I know, I know.
哦，伙计。
你老婆真差劲
Oh, man.
Your wife sucks.
嘿，嘿，沃尔特，
这可不太好
Hey, hey, WaIter,
that is not cooI.
- 咱们还在商务会议中
- 对不起，伙计
- We're stiII in a business meeting.
- I'm sorry, man.
只是这衣服也太他妈热了
It's just this suit
is so friggin' hot.
对不起，伙计们。
我是说，你们做得很好，真的
I'm sorry, guys. I mean, you did
a good job, reaIIy.
- 就这样？你不来了？
- 是的，我想
- So that's it? You're out?
- Yeah, I think.
哦，你知道，
Oh, you know,
我需要你们把支票还给我
I'm gonna need
that check back.
什么？
What?
两星期前我给你们的定金。
我需要拿回来
That deposit I gave you a coupIe
weeks ago. I'm gonna need it back.
哦，是的，定金
Oh, yeah, the deposit.
是的，没了
Yeah, it's gone.
什么意思没了？
What do you mean, gone?
唔，你知道，
全花在演示上了
WeII, you know, spent it
on the whoIe presentation.
制服、黑板架。
这也是新的
The suit, the easeI.
This is new.
你全花了？
1000块？
You spent aII of it?
A thousand doIIars?
你怎么能这样？
How couId you do that?
我告诉过你，
我们今天来只为了
I just toId you, the onIy reason
we came here today,
能得到更多的钱
was to get more money.
哦，我的天，我怎么告诉黛比拉
我损失了1000块
Oh my God, how am I gonna teII Debra
I Iost a thousand doIIars?
我可再也不跟她说话了
I wouIdn't taIk
to her anymore.
- 嘿，你好呀，美国少女小姐
- 嘿
- Hey, there, Miss Teen USA.
- Hey.
嘿
Hey.
那是什么，床上的新毯子？
看着真不错
What are those, new sheets in the bed?
Those Iook nice.
- 那不是新的
- 哦
- They're not new.
- Oh.
唔，有种不错的特质
WeII, something about 'em
Iooks nice.
也许是因为盖着的人
Maybe it's the person in 'em.
你打什么主意呢，雷？
嘿咻还是高尔夫？
What are you after, Ray?
Sex or goIf?
都不是
Neither.
天
Jeez.
男人就不能欣赏织物？
Can't a guy admire Iinens?
嘿，你知道――
Hey, you know--
还记得――
remember--
还记得咱们去的
那个城里的餐厅吗？
remember that restaurant
we went to in the city
一个人直接上来要钱，
我没带――
and the guy out front was asking
for money and I didn't have any--
我没零钱，所以你给了他个5块？
I didn't have change
so you gave him a five?
是的，我记得
Yeah, I remember that.
你还想拿回来，
然后他就跑了
He ran away after you tried
to get it back from him.
是啊
Yeah.
不过然后我意识到，
他比咱们更需要这笔钱，
But then I reaIized,
he needed it more than we did
然后就不追他了
and I stopped
chasing him.
- 咱们都喜欢那段回忆
- 是啊
- We aII have fond memories of that day.
- Yeah.
我刚刚想到这件事，
I was just thinking of that,
因为我最近做了一件
类似的事情
'cause I did something
simiIar recentIy.
- 是吗？
- 是的
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
我给了司各特和沃尔特1000块
I gave Scott and WaIter
a thousand doIIars.
什么？！
What?!
好了，听着，我知道你听了
会不高兴――
Okay, Iook, I know you're gonna
get upset about this--
天哪！
1000块？！
My God!
A thousand doIIars?!
想想那个快乐的流浪汉
Remember the happy hobo.
我给了他5块钱！
I have him $5!
好吧，可是对流浪汉来说，
这就像是1000块了
Okay, but to a hobo,
that's Iike a thousand.
这么说我叫你别给他们钱
So you gave
Scott and WaIter money
你还是给了？
after I asked you not to?
不，我是在你
叫我别给之前给的
No, I gave it to 'em
before you asked me not to.
你怎么能这样？
How couId you do that?
- 对不起，我会把钱要回来的
- 不是钱的事！
- I'm sorry, I'II get the money back.
- It's not about the money!
那我就不理解
这么怨恨的叫嚷是怎么回事了
Then I reaIIy don't understand
the hatefuI screaming.
你对我就这么不尊重，
You reaIIy have so IittIe
respect for me,
做这种事连问都不问我？
that you wouId do that
without asking me?
- 我尊重你
- 显然不是！
- I respect you.
- ObviousIy not!
你说都没跟我说就开支票了！
You wrote the check before you
even taIked to me about it!
- 因为我以为你会同意的！
- 唔，我不同意！
- Because I though you wouId say yes!
- WeII, I'm saying no!
好吧，是你改主意了！
Okay, you changed
your mind!
那么你想――回到让你看着
好极了的毯子里吗？
So you wanna-- get back in the sheets
where you Iook so nice?
我真不相信你会这么做！
I can't beIieve
you did this!
好吧，听着，我错了
Okay, Iisten,
I screwed up.
我是说，我乱花的也是我的钱
Okay, but it's my money
to screw up with.
你说什么？
What did you say?
乱搞的什么――？
With which to screw up--?
什么？我说的什么？
What? What did I say?
你要是在装东西的话，
我这还有几双袜子！
If you're doing a Ioad,
I got some socks!
难怪了！
No wonder!
嘿，这怎么调的59度？
Hey, why is this on 59?
我昨晚上盖太多，热坏了
I was hot Iast night with
aII those covers on me.
怎么了？你睡得不舒服？
Why? Were you
uncomfortabIe?
不。我盖了毛巾和浴室门垫
No. I had a toweI
and a bath mat.
睡得像个宝宝
I sIept Iike a baby.
- 给
- 这是什么？
- Here.
- What's this?
我昨晚做出来的点东西
A IittIe something
I worked up Iast night.
“洗衣，75块一星期
''Laundry, $75 a week.
大扫除，
GeneraI housecIeaning,
200块一星期”
$200 a week.''
- 这是什么，账单？
- 没错
- What is this, a biII?
- That's right.
“全天照料孩子，
1000块一星期”
''FuII time chiId care,
a thousand doIIars a week.''
是的，这项上我给你优惠了
Yeah, I gave you
a break on that one.
双胞胎我只算了一件
I biIIed the twins
as one item.
那么，你要我付你钱
做妻子了？
So, you're charging
me now, to be the wife?
唔，如果钱都是你的，
那么做“妻子”的应该有工钱
WeII, if it's aII your money,
then ''the wife'' shouId get paid.
啊哈
Uh-huh.
“私人厨师，300块”
''PersonaI chef, $300.
我想“厨师”这个词用得也太不严格了
I think we're using the word ''chef''
pretty IooseIy.
嘿
Hey.
我给爱丽订的
女童子军曲奇到了吗？
Those GirI Scout cookies
I ordered from AIIy come in yet?
- 不，还没呢
- 该死……
- No, not yet.
- Damn...
我这是想当追随者
（想要Tagalong体育器材）吗？
am I jonesin'
for a ''TagaIong.''
吃点Hydrox（奶油夹心饼），
别难过了
Have a Hydrox,
take the edge off.
在这等着，我给你拿个七彩吊裤带
Wait here, I'II get you a pair
of rainbow suspenders.
你可以去牛仔比赛上做小丑了
You can be a rodeo cIown.
是吗，唔，昨晚这里有点冷
Yeah, weII, it got a IittIe chiIIy here
Iast night.
嘿，你戴个帽子干嘛？
Hey, what are you
doing with that cap?
哦，是的！卡丁冲击。
我猜咱们是合伙人了
Oh, yeah! Kart Attack.
I guess you and me are partners now.
哦，这么说你也投资了
Oh, so you invested too.
你开玩笑吗？
那两个伙计的演示很出色
Are you kidding me?
Those guys did a great presentation,
一下把我震住了。
烟雾机都有，什么都用上了
BIew me away.
Fog machine and everything.
那你的帽子呢，雷？
Where's your hat, Ray?
怎么不戴戴你1000块的帽子？
Why don't you put on
your thousand-doIIar hat?
你怎么不给我来碗
300块的麦片呢？
Why don't you pour me
a $300 bowI of cereaI?
你应该戴戴你的帽子，雷，
免费的广告
You shouId wear the hat,
Ray, free advertising.
唔，我不知道我能不能戴帽子
WeII, I don't know
if I can wear a hat.
我还没申请许可呢
I haven't asked
permission yet.
嘿，罗伯特可以随便
拿他的钱投资
Hey, Robert can invest
his money however he wants.
他没结婚，
就他一个人
He's not married,
he's aIone.
嘟哒，嘟哒……
Doo-dah, doo-dah...
是啊
Yeah.
别担心，罗伯特，
你这样还好。看看这个
Don't worry, Robert,
you're better off. Look at this.
这单子是我妻子给我的，
Here's a Iist
my wife gave me
要我为娶她付钱
of what she's charging
me to be married to her.
喔啊――知道吗，黛比拉？
Whoa-- you know what, Debra?
- 字写得真漂亮
- 谢谢
- You have beautifuI handwriting.
- Thank you.
拜托！不是说字的问题
Come on! It's not about
the handwriting.
看看她都找我
要什么钱！
Look at what she's
charging me for!
这个数是个什么意思？
What the heII is that
number right there?
一财年的总计
That's the totaI
for the fiscaI year.
这比我挣得还多！
That's more than I earn!
哦，你注意到了？
Oh, you noticed that?
是吗，可事实是得我来挣
Yeah, but I actuaIIy earn it.
嗨，亲爱的
Hi, dears.
黛比拉，我需要借你的洗衣机用用
Debra, I need
to borrow your washer.
- 弗兰克把我们的弄坏了
- 没坏
- Frank broke ours.
- It's not broken.
你放进去之前，
让我把他们的拆了
Before you put that in,
Iet me take theirs apart
好看看应该是什么样的
so I can see what it's supposed
to Iook Iike.
看，我们这有点事
Look, we're kinda
in the middIe of something here,
所以你们能不能
过几年再过来？
so couId you come back
in a coupIe of years?
你在做什么？
在浴缸里做私酒呢？
What are you doing?
Making moonshine in the bathtub?
我给你买的那套
有棒球手的
Where are those
nice pajamas
好看的睡衣呢？
with the basebaII
pIayers I got you?
- 这是什么？
- 你想知道这是什么？
- What's this?
- You wanna know what that is?
好的，我来告诉你这是什么，玛丽
Yeah, I'II teII you
what that is, Marie.
你是家庭主妇，
就像我
You're a homemaker,
Iike me.
好吧
Okay.
你不认为你在家庭的财政决定上
Don't you think that you're entitIed
to an equaI say
- 有平等的说话权吗？
- 绝对的，亲爱的
- in your famiIy's financiaI decisions?
- AbsoIuteIy, dear.
我列的这张单子
就是要让雷明白这点
This is a Iist I put together
to make that point with Ray.
看她的7上加了一横。
多好看哪！
Look how she puts a Iine
through her sevens. Isn't that nice?
怎么了？
What?
只是看着有些――
Just Iooking through
some of this--
你宣称你做的家务活
housekeeping things
you cIaim you do.
我想也许我也有权分到些
这里头的钱
I think maybe I'm entitIed
to some of this money.
看来有人在报虚账
Looks Iike someone's
padding the biII.
看，雷，有人闯进来打扫
Look, Ray,
I can't heIp it
我有什么办法呢？
if peopIe break in here
and cIean.
是的，唔，你说的“进来”的地方，
Yeah, weII, the ''in here''
you're taIking about
指的是咱们用
我的工资买的房子
is the house we bought
with my paycheck.
你是说你比我更有价值
Are you saying you're
more vaIuabIe than me
因为你能往家带工资条？
because you bring
home a paycheck?
我没这么说。
我想是社会那么说的
I'm not saying that.
I think society says that.
好吗？
你应该去跟他们说
AII right?
You shouId taIk to them.
事实上，雷蒙德，
判断一个人生命
ActuaIIy, Raymond,
the best way to determine
的价值的最好方法
the vaIue of someone's Iife
- 就是过失致死赔偿
- 哦，很好
- is with a wrongfuI death settIement.
- Oh, good.
很好，因为我们
这就要发生一件了
Good, 'cause we're about
to have one.
不，真的，我约会过一个
过失致死索赔评定人
No, reaIIy, I dated a wrongfuI
death cIaims adjuster.
她的工作是算出
And it was her job
to figure out
如果一个被爱的家人
死于意外
what a jury
wouId award a famiIy
陪审团该判
赔偿这个家庭多少
if a Ioved one were
kiIIed an accident.
换句话说，
他们值多少
In other words,
what they were worth.
想想她都得考虑些什么，
有意思极了
It was fascinating to see
what she had to consider.
没敢再跟她约第二次，
不过很有意思
Too morbid for a second
date, but fascinating.
比如什么？
Like what?
比如他们考虑你是个什么样的人
Like they consider what kind of person
you were.
就拿爸来说吧
Take Dad,
for exampIe.
假设有人把钢琴砸他头上了
Let's say someone
dropped a piano on him.
好吧
Okay.
陪审团将考虑
他是如何生活的
A jury wouId be asked to consider
what kind of Iife he Ied.
他是不是个快乐的人？
他有没有给别人带来快乐？
Was he a happy person?
Did he bring joy to others?
他会不会停下来闻玫瑰花？
Did he stop
and smeII the roses?
是的，是的，是的
Yes, yes and yes.
你才不热爱生活！
You don't enjoy Iife!
你天天下午锁在
洗澡间里3个小时
You spend three hours every afternoon
Iocked in the bathroom.
躲着你，
我就是这样享受生活的！
Hiding from you,
that's how I enjoy Iife!
所以，我们可以认为
他值不了太多
So, we can assume
he wouIdn't fetch much.
妈会好点
Mom wouId fare
sIightIy better
因为他们会把痛苦和忍受
考虑进去
because they factor in
pain and suffering.
是，好吧，咱们都知道他们值多少
Yeah, aII right, we aII know
what they're worth.
那我和黛比拉谁会赢？
But who wouId win
between me and Debra?
唔，咱们在说的是死亡，
雷蒙德
WeII, we're taIking
about death here, Raymond.
这可不会有赢家
There's reaIIy
no winning.
好吧，说得对，
谁值得多？
Okay, yeah,
who's worth more?
这就有点复杂了
It's a IittIe compIicated.
我是说，陪审团可能考虑任何事
I mean, a jury couId Iook
at aImost anything.
比如说，你知不知道
For exampIe,
did you know
他们对有魅力的人更同情？
that they're more sympathetic
to an attractive person?
傻眼了吧，雷密欧
Say good night,
Ray-mo.
我相信如果把戴比拉的生命
呈现给陪审员，他们会看到
I'm sure if Debra's Iife was
presented to a jury, they wouId see
- 她充满活力
- 是，是，好吧
- that she was very active.
- Yeah, yeah, okay.
她勤劳、健康、
That she worked out,
she was heaIthy,
精神饱满、疯狂的热爱生活――
spirited, she had
a zest for Iife--
知道了！
Got it!
并且他们会更同情黛比拉因为
And they wouId aIso be
more sympathetic to Debra
她是主要的照料和养育者
because she is the primary
caregiver and nurturer.
我胜出
I win.
等等――等一下，
等一等，那我呢？
Wait-- wait a minute,
wait a minute, what about me?
晤，雷蒙德，我猜
WeII, Raymond, I guess
你是经济上的供给者
you're the financiaI provider.
说的对极了。
奶酪是我挣的
Damn straight.
I make the cheddar, baby.
是的。还有什么？
Yeah. What eIse?
嗯……
Um...
我不知道
I don't know.
拜托！
Come on!
我――我热爱生活
I-- I enjoy Iife.
我疯狂的热爱生活。
我疯狂透了
I have a zest for Iife.
I'm totaIIy zesty.
我的幽默感呢，哈？
这个怎么样？
How about my sense of humor, huh?
How about that?
怎么样？
What about it?
我很有幽默感，出色的幽默感
I have a good one.
I have a good sense of humor.
是真的。
讲个你的笑话，亲爱的
That is true.
TeII one of your jokes, dear.
什么？讲哪个？
What? Which one?
就讲那个
一个人
TeII the one about the guy
走进酒吧，
who goes into a bar,
一盘花生拍起了他的马屁
and there's a dish of peanuts
that says nice things to him.
他问酒保：
“这些花生是怎么了？”
And he asks the bartender
''What's with these peanuts?''
酒保说：
“它们是免费的（马屁精）”
And the bartender says
''They're compIimentary.''
就讲那个
TeII that one, dear.
你――你刚说了，妈
You-- you just toId it, Ma.
不，不。 你讲起来好笑极了
No, no. You teII it so funny.
你把结尾都说了，妈
You just toId
the ending, Ma.
唔，那就讲开头。
我喜欢你――
WeII, teII the beginning.
I Iove it when you--
妈，我不会讲这个，
因为你把好笑的那句都抖出来了！
Ma, I'm not teIIing the joke
because you bIew the punch Iine!
- 你明白吗？
- 好吧，好吧！
- You understand that?
- AII right, aII right!
- 疯狂的热爱生活
- 她说了“它们是马屁精”
- What a zest for Iife.
- She said ''They're compIimentary''!
好笑的就在这了！
That's the whoIe joke!
别给自己辩护了
Stop defending yourseIf.
你往家带工资
You bring home
the paycheck.
往家带工资的人
就是国王
Whoever brings home
the money is the king.
- 讨论结束
- 说得好，父亲。看到了？
- End of story.
- WeII put, Father. You see?
他可以随便处置钱
He can do whatever he wants
with the money.
呃呵――玛丽，
你没有不舒服吗？
Ugh-- Marie,
doesn't that bother you?
她没的选择
She has no choice
in the matter.
我是国王
I am the king.
而现在，陛下要回城堡了
And now, His Majesty
wiII retire to his castIe,
他会在那等着
王室奶酪烤三明治
where he wiII await
the royaI griIIed cheese sandwich.
快走，傻子！
你逗我开心
Come, oaf!
You amuse me.
我到地狱里见你
I'II see you in heII.
玛丽，你怎么能让他这么说？
Marie, how can you
Iet him taIk that way?
弗兰克想怎么说都没关系，
Frank can say
whatever he wants,
他从来没掌握钱
he never controIIed
the money.
他把工资条给我，
我怎么花都行
When he brought home a paycheck,
I did whatever I wanted with it.
你说什么呢？
爸爸可不知道这个
What are you taIking about?
Dad had no idea about that.
不，有时候他也会打听起来
No, sometimes
he'd get nosy.
不过然后我就给他做顿
丰盛的晚餐
But I'd make him
a heavy dinner
然后他就在沙发上睡着了
and then he'd faII asIeep
on the couch
然后我又把钱调配起来了
and I started moving
the money around.
阴险
DiaboIicaI.
他天真的程度
还真是惊人
It's amazing
how cIueIess he is.
你知道吗，有30多年了，
Do you know
that for more than 30 years
我一直在送钱给
I've been giving money
南美的孩子买书？
to buy books
for chiIdren in South America?
你认为你爸会同意这么做吗？
You think your father
wouId have approved of that?
他连给我们的书都不想买
He didn't Iike
buying us books.
他――他从不知道我存的
He-- he never knew about
aII that money I saved
咱们去意大利的钱。
另外，黛比拉，
for our trip to ItaIy.
And Debra,
我从没告诉弗兰克
我借给你们俩的钱
I never toId Frank
about the Ioan I gave you two.
- 借什么钱？
- 没事的，玛丽，
- What Ioan?
- That's okay, Marie,
你不用――
you don't have to--
你们俩刚结婚的时候，
住在那个小公寓里
When you first got married
and you were Iiving in that apartment.
- 什么钱？
- 不，那个――那没多少
- What Ioan?
- No, it-- it wasn't much.
只是一点让咱们度过难关的钱
It was just a IittIe something
to get us over a rough spot.
是的，亲爱的，
只有2500块
Yes, dear,
it was just $2,500.
哦！
Ooh!
2500块？你――
你从没跟我说过
$2,500? You-- you
never toId me about that.
是的，可你需要新轮胎，
咱们的洗碗机也坏了，
Yeah, but we needed new tires
and the dishwasher was broken
而你又还没拿到奖金
and you hadn't gotten
your bonus yet.
- 你已经尽力了
- 所以你就找我妈了？！
- And you were doing the best you couId.
- So you went to my mother?!
我告诉黛比拉她不用还的，
她是家里人
I toId Debra she didn't have
to pay me back, she's famiIy.
爱是不能用钱衡量的。
再说――
And you can't put
a price on Iove. And anyway--
- 我也不是那种――
- 我两星期后就还她了
- I'm not the kind of person--
- I paid her back in two weeks.
你的生活因为
玛丽・巴伦基金的拨款
Your Iife made possibIe
by a grant
而得以延续
from the Marie Barone
Foundation.
天。你还做了什么？
My God. What eIse
did you do?
还有什么我不知道的？
What eIse don't
I know about?
- 没有了
- 得了吧。如果你能做出
- Nothing.
- Come on. If you can do things
向我妈借钱这样的事，
还有什么钱方面的事
Iike borrow money from my mother,
what other money stuff
- 是我不知道的？
- 没了
- don't I know about?
- Nothing.
看，你做了卡丁车的事，
Look, you did
the go-cart thing
我做了你妈那件事，就那一次
and I did the thing
with your mother that one time.
所以――你知道，
咱们扯平了
So-- you know,
we're even.
喔啊！
等一等！
Whoa!
Wait a minute!
看看你周围，雷蒙德，
你很幸福
Look around, Raymond,
you got it good.
- 不管她做的什么都不是瞎搞
- 不不不
- Whatever she's doing is working.
- No, no, no.
- 真的，你还做了什么？
- 雷蒙德……
- ReaIIy, what eIse did you do?
- Raymond...
嘿，嘿，嘿，
听着，阿扁。
Hey, hey, hey,
Iisten, cubby.
一只猴子拉个铃，
然后出来了小球，
When the IittIe monkey rings a beII
and the peIIet comes out,
小猴子不会问
小球是怎么来的，
he doesn't ask
how the peIIet got there.
它只会好好玩它的球
He just enjoys
the peIIet.
你知道吗？
也许你是对的
You know what?
Maybe you were right.
我只是说，也许咱们是该
I'm just saying, maybe we shouId
consuIt each other now
- 商量所有的钱的事情了，好吗？
- 好吧，好的，当然
- in aII the money stuff, okay?
- AII right, okay, sure.
- 哦，太好了
- 是啊
- Oh, that's so nice.
- Yeah.
亲爱的，不如你坐到沙发上吧？
Honey, why don't you
just go sit on the couch?
- 我给你做顿好吃的，怎么样？
- 好吧
- I'II make you a nice meaI, okay?
- AII right.
美味而丰盛
Nice and heavy.
听着，我想参与到所有事情，
好吗？
Listen, I want to be incIuded
in everything, okay?
- 所有决定，好吗？
- 绝对的
- In aII the decisions, okay?
- DefiniteIy.
走了
Let's go.
- 我为她工作，不是吗？
- 嗯哼
- I work for her, don't I?
- Mm-hmm.
嘿，玛丽！
Hey, Marie!
谁是米盖尔・乌拉斯格子？
Who the heII is
MigueI VeIasquez?
他说的好奇乔治是什么狗屁？
And what is this crap he's saying
about Curious George?
我做了火鸡奶酪蘑菇面
I got turkey tetrazzini.
- 哦，嘿！
- 吃吧
- Ooh, hey!
- There you are.
jojoba
yettoreturn@hotmail.com